### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

I am a Senior Digital Designer and a user experience enthusiast. I enjoy working across multiple platforms to create solutions that are both captivating and easy to use.

I have been working in the online industry for almost 8 years. Currently specialising in user-centered design methodologies, I'm looking for a position where I can put into practice my recent and collective knowledge. My goal is to find the best user-centered solution within a given constraint.

### **CURRENTLY**

Working at The New Zealand Herald. APN News Media, Auckland.

Completed a UX course at Billy Blue College. Ultimo, Sydney.

### **MOST ACTIVE TECH SKILLS**

Adobe Creative Suite. Photoshop. Illustrator. Indesign. Flash.

User flow & Prototyping. Axure. UXpin.

Development. HTML5. CSS3. Sass/Susy. Jquery. Git. Sublime.

### **ABILITIES**

### **User Experience Methodologies.**

Discovery of the best solutions through personas, user journeys, wireframes, prototypes, testing and iteration.

### Visual and Interface Design.

Conversion of solutions into engaging and compelling visual designs.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# Senior Digital Designer - The New Zealand Herald

FEB 2011 - PRESENT

Currently creating unique user experiences, custom design and development for both desktop and mobile; designing solutions to display complex information; researching user needs and designing interactions to introduce new products; working across teams to find the best design solution.

- Front end development.
- Applying user experience methodologies.
- Working with editorial on special coverages.

#### **SOFTWARE:**

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE - HTML5 CSS3 - SASS - GIT - MAPBOX - CARTODB - TABLEAU - AXURE

### Web Designer - Moko Digital

NOV 2009 - OCT 2010

Created concepts, visual designs for websites and branding, as well as small custom developments. Mostly worked as a team to find solutions to evolve our client's brand online.

- · Visual design.
- Development.

#### **SOFTWARE:**

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE - HTML5 CSS3 - JQUERY - FLASH - VISUAL STUDIO

## Designer for Web and Print - Trio Group

APR 2007 - NOV 2009

Designed for print and some digital edition work. Pre-press checks before production. Worked for renowned brands like Air New Zealand and Coca-Cola Amatil.

### Print and Digital Editions

#### **SOFTWARE:**

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE - HTML5 CSS3 - FLASH - ADOBE ACROBAT

# Designer for Web and Print | APN News and Media, Finda

MAR 2006 - APR 2007

Designed advertising for print and web; customised maps. Used their CMS and sometimes custom HTML to put online adverts on Wises Maps, Sella and Finda. Helped to create a workflow to convert print to online using XML in InDesign.

• Design for print and some custom HTML.

#### **SOFTWARE:**

ILLUSTRATOR - PHOTOSHOP - INDESIGN - ADOBE ACROBAT - HTML - FLASH

# Graphic Designer - Ponto Forte Comunicações

MAR 2001 - FEB 2003

Designed for print and followed guidelines from brands and art directors. Experienced the design world first hand and developed my skills as a designer working on top Brazilian brands.

- Designed following briefs and brand guidelines.
- Print and Mac Operator tasks.

#### **SOFTWARE:**

ILLUSTRATOR - PHOTOSHOP - QUARKXPRESS - ADOBE ACROBAT

#### **AWARDS**

## Best Innovation in Multimedia (2012)

Canon Media Awards - AUCKLAND

*In recognition for all round excellence of work.* 

### **EDUCATION AND COURSES**

# UX Design & Research - Billy Blue College of Design - SYDNEY

MAY 2015

Practical and theoretical skills to research, design and test websites. Industry best-practices and tools for researching, designing and testing. Hands on practical projects. Planning, interaction design and usability testing.

- Design research (Persona and customer journey maps).
- Wireframes and interactive prototypes (Axure).
- Usability testing and reports.

### UX Crash Course - Design Assembly - AUCKLAND

**APRIL 2015** 

Hands-on experience of a digital UX design project from start to finish. In this intense workshop I was given practical experience about some of the most common activities in a typical user-centered digital design process.

- Experience user research.
- Ideation and interaction design.
- · Rapid prototyping and user testing.

# $Diploma\ of\ Digital\ Media\ (\textit{with\ distinction})\ -\ \texttt{MDS\ School\ -\ AUCKLAND}$

APR 2008 - FEB 2010

How to communicate using text, images and forms to create interactions. Graphic, motion and interactive design. PHP, ActionScript, Video Editing, Flash and Animation graphics.

- Web design best practices.
- Design and development.
- Video, sound editing and animation.

Formed part of the industry panel in 2012

# Technologies for Multimedia - School of Visual Arts - BA

DEC 1999

Provided us with the knowledge and skills relating to graphics, audio, video, animation and web. This programme aimed to provide a broad range approach to digital media.

- Digital illustration, animation and storyboarding.
- Digital imaging and video editing.

# Graphic Designer - UM University - BUENOS AIRES

DEC 1999 - OCT 2000

Conceptualisation and production of visual material that effectively communicate information and ideas for a wide range of media.

- · Design foundations: Typography, grids, color theory.
- Composition and images, editorial and layout.

# Graphic Designer - Polytechnic Fernando Fader BA

MAR 1990 - DEC 1996

Techniques and methodologies for design and promotion. This is a general foundation course running for three years with high school content and another three years of design specialisation.

### **SKILLS SUMMARY**

PHOTOSHOP:	EXPERT	•••••
<b>ILLUSTRATOR:</b>	EXPERT	•••••
INDESIGN:	ADVANCED	•••••
AXURE:	INTERMEDIATE	••••
FLASH:	ADVANCED	•••••
DREAMWEAVER:	INTERMEDIATE	••••000
SUBLIME:	INTERMEDIATE	••••000
CSS <sub>3</sub>   HTML <sub>5</sub> :	ADVANCED	•••••
GIT:	BASIC	••00000
SASS   SUSY:	INTERMEDIATE	•••••
JAVASCRIPT:	BASIC	••00000
JQUERY:	INTERMEDIATE	••••000
ACTIONSCRIPT:	ADVANCED	•••••
TABLEAU:	INTERMEDIATE	••••
<b>MAPPING:</b>	INTERMEDIATE	••••
DATA VIZ:	INTERMEDIATE	••••

#### **PERSONAL**

I am a New Zealander, originally from Argentina. I have been living in New Zealand for 11 years but I intend to move to Sydney permanently. My passions are design, art, yoga and dancing -currently learning tango. I'm coming to Sydney regularly to visit my friends and enjoy the dancing scene.